<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?><!DOCTYPE collection SYSTEM 'BioC.dtd'><collection><source>PubTator</source><date></date><key>BioC.key</key><document><id>31095519</id><passage><infon key="journal">J Water Health; 2019 Jun1 1713) 442-454. doi:10.2166/wh.2019.304</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">wh_2019_304</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">de Deus DR, Teixeira DM, Dos Santos Alves JC, Smith VC, da Silva Bandeira R, Siqueira JAM, de Sá Morais LLC, Resque HR, Gabbay YB, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>Occurrence of norovirus genogroups I and II in recreational water from four beaches in Belem city, Brazilian Amazon region.</text></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>124</offset><text>This study aimed to investigate the presence of norovirus (NoV) in recreational waters of four estuarine beaches located in Mosqueiro Island, Belem city, Brazilian Amazon, during two years of monitoring (2012 and 2013). NoV particles were concentrated on filtering membrane by the adsorption-elution method and detected by semi-nested RT-PCR (reverse transcription polymerase chain reaction) and sequencing. NoV positivity was observed in 37.5% (39/104) of the surface water samples, with genogroup GI (69.2%) occurring at a higher frequency than GII (25.7%), with a cocirculation of both genogroups in two samples (5.1%). This virus was detected in all sampling points analyzed, showing the highest detection rate at the Paraiso Beach (46.2%). Statistically, there was a dependence relationship between tide levels and positive detection, with a higher frequency at high tide (46.7%) than at low tide (25%) periods. Months with the highest detection rates (April 2012 and April/May 2013) were preceded by periods of higher precipitation (March 2012 and February/March 2013). Phylogenetic analysis showed the circulation of the old pandemic variant (GII.4-US_95-96) and GI.8. The NoV detection demonstrated viral contamination on the beaches and evidenced the health risk to bathers, mainly through recreational activities such as bathing, and highlighted the importance of including enteric viruses research in the recreational water quality monitoring.</text><annotation id="2"><infon key="identifier">12081</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="5" offset="752"/><text>virus</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="identifier">10239</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="1516"/><text>viruses</text></annotation></passage></document><document><id>31096052</id><passage><infon key="journal">Int. J. Infect. Dis.; 2019 May 131 doi:10.1016/j.ijid.2019.05.005</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">Barnes CE, MacIntyre CR, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>Risk modeling the mortality impact of antimicrobial resistance in secondary pneumococcal pneumonia infections during the 2009 influenza pandemic.</text><annotation id="1"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D011018</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="33" offset="76"/><text>pneumococcal pneumonia infections</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>146</offset><text>OBJECTIVES: The aim of this study was to estimate the impact of antimicrobial resistance (AMR) in secondary pneumococcal pneumonia infections on global mortality during the 2009 influenza pandemic, to estimate future pandemic mortality risk and to inform pandemic preparedness. METHODS: Risk analysis modeling was conducted using a multivariate risk formula. Literature reviews were conducted to generate global central estimates for each of the parameters of the risk formula in relation to the 2009 influenza pandemic, secondary pneumococcal pneumonia, rates of AMR and pneumococcal vaccine efficacy as a component of pandemic preparedness. RESULTS: Global Streptococcus pneumoniae AMR was estimated at 21.8% to 27.6%, and contributed to 1.8% to 2.3% of deaths during the 2009 influenza pandemic. When directly applied to mortality due to multidrug resistance, pneumococcal vaccination could potentially prevent 1,277 to 3,754 deaths and could have reduced mortality from multidrug resistant S. pneumoniae to 1% to 1.2%. CONCLUSION: AMR in secondary pneumococcal infections contributed towards a small percentage of the global mortality during the 2009 influenza pandemic. Increased S. pnuemoniae AMR could result in a three- to four-fold rise in mortality due to secondary pneumococcal infections in future influenza pandemics. Pneumococcal vaccination has an important role in preventing pneumococcal co-infections and combating AMR in all populations, and should be considered a key component of influenza pandemic preparedness or early action plans.</text><annotation id="14"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D011018</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="33" offset="254"/><text>pneumococcal pneumonia infections</text></annotation><annotation id="15"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D011018</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="22" offset="677"/><text>pneumococcal pneumonia</text></annotation><annotation id="16"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D011008</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="12" offset="718"/><text>pneumococcal</text></annotation><annotation id="17"><infon key="identifier">1313</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="24" offset="805"/><text>Streptococcus pneumoniae</text></annotation><annotation id="18"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003643</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="6" offset="902"/><text>deaths</text></annotation><annotation id="19"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D011008</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="12" offset="1009"/><text>pneumococcal</text></annotation><annotation id="20"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003643</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="6" offset="1075"/><text>deaths</text></annotation><annotation id="21"><infon key="identifier">2104</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="13" offset="1140"/><text>S. pneumoniae</text></annotation><annotation id="22"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D011008</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="23" offset="1198"/><text>pneumococcal infections</text></annotation><annotation id="23"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D011008</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="23" offset="1422"/><text>pneumococcal infections</text></annotation><annotation id="24"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D060085</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="26" offset="1538"/><text>pneumococcal co-infections</text></annotation><annotation id="25"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D007251</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="31" offset="1647"/><text>influenza pandemic preparedness</text></annotation></passage></document><document><id>31097871</id><passage><infon key="journal">Can. J. Vet. Res.; 2019 Apr1 8312) 97-103</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">Chung HC, Nguyen VG, Le Huynh TM, Moon HJ, Kang BK, Kim SJ, Kim HK, Park SJ, Park KT, Park YH, Park BK, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>Molecular characterization of a Korean porcine epidemic diarrhea virus strain NB1.</text><annotation id="2"><infon key="identifier">28295</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="31" offset="39"/><text>porcine epidemic diarrhea virus</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="identifier">57126</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="NCBI Homologene">49628</infon><location length="3" offset="78"/><text>NB1</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>83</offset><text>In Korea, for the past 30 years (1987-present), porcine epidemic diarrhea (PED) has been established as an endemic situation in which multiple genogroups of classical G1 and G2b, and the recently introduced pandemic G2a, coexisted. Because of the dynamic nature of the virus, continuous field monitoring for PEDV strains is required. This study is the first to reveal prevalence of PEDV in 9 sampling provinces, with an overall detection rate of 6.70%. Porcine endemic diarrhea virus (PEDV) was present in pigs of all ages, especially in the non-PED vaccinated groups. The highest detection rate was in the finisher group (2.34%), followed by that in the newborn group (1.56%). Secondly, using Sanger sequencing, this study recovered a complete genome (28 005 nucleotides long) of NB1 strain from a farm severely affected by PED. Analyses of nucleotide and deduced amino acid sequences showed that NB1 differed from 18 other Korean PEDV mostly in 4 protein coding genes: ORF1a, ORF1b, S, and N. Two amino acid substitutions (V635E and Y681Q) in the COE and S1D neutralizing epitopes of NB1 resulted in antigenic index alteration of the adjacent sites, one of which contributed to a mutation that escaped neutralizing antibodies.</text><annotation id="19"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003967</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="17" offset="139"/><text>epidemic diarrhea</text></annotation><annotation id="20"><infon key="identifier">12081</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="5" offset="352"/><text>virus</text></annotation><annotation id="21"><infon key="identifier">28295</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="4" offset="391"/><text>PEDV</text></annotation><annotation id="22"><infon key="identifier">28295</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="4" offset="465"/><text>PEDV</text></annotation><annotation id="23"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003967</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="8" offset="552"/><text>diarrhea</text></annotation><annotation id="24"><infon key="identifier">12081</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="5" offset="561"/><text>virus</text></annotation><annotation id="25"><infon key="identifier">28295</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="4" offset="568"/><text>PEDV</text></annotation><annotation id="26"><infon key="identifier">9823</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="4" offset="589"/><text>pigs</text></annotation><annotation id="27"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="738"/><text>newborn</text></annotation><annotation id="28"><infon key="identifier">57126</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="NCBI Homologene">49628</infon><location length="3" offset="864"/><text>NB1</text></annotation><annotation id="29"><infon key="identifier">57126</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="NCBI Homologene">49628</infon><location length="3" offset="981"/><text>NB1</text></annotation><annotation id="30"><infon key="identifier">28295</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="4" offset="1015"/><text>PEDV</text></annotation><annotation id="31"><infon key="Identifier">p.V635E;CorrespondingGene:57126</infon><infon key="type">ProteinMutation</infon><location length="5" offset="1108"/><text>V635E</text></annotation><annotation id="32"><infon key="Identifier">p.Y681Q;CorrespondingGene:57126</infon><infon key="type">ProteinMutation</infon><location length="5" offset="1118"/><text>Y681Q</text></annotation><annotation id="33"><infon key="identifier">57126</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="NCBI Homologene">49628</infon><location length="3" offset="1169"/><text>NB1</text></annotation></passage></document><document><id>31102651</id><passage><infon key="journal">Insect Biochem. Mol. Biol.; 2019 May 151 doi:10.1016/j.ibmb.2019.05.003</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">Chen W, Wosula EN, Hasegawa DK, Casinga C, Shirima RR, Fiaboe KKM, Hanna R, Fosto A, Goergen G, Tamò M, Mahuku G, Murithi HM, Tripathi L, Mware B, Kumar LP, Ntawuruhunga P, Moyo C, Yomeni M, Boahen S, Edet M, Awoyale W, Wintermantel WM, Ling KS, Legg JP, Fei Z, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>Genome of the African cassava whitefly Bemisia tabaci and distribution and genetic diversity of cassava-colonizing whiteflies in Africa.</text><annotation id="2"><infon key="identifier">7038</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="14" offset="39"/><text>Bemisia tabaci</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="96"/><text>cassava</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>137</offset><text>The whitefy Bemisia tabaci, a species complex consisting of many morphologically indistinguishable species divided into distinct clades, is one of the most globally important agricultural pests and plant virus vectors. Cassava-colonizing B. tabaci transmits viruses that cause cassava mosaic disease (CMD) and cassava brown streak disease (CBSD). Half of all cassava plants in Africa are affected by these viral diseases, resulting in annual production losses of more than US$ 1 billion. Here we report the draft genome of the cassava whitefly B. tabaci Sub-Saharan Africa - East and Central Africa (SSA-ECA), the super-abundant population that has been associated with the rapid spread of viruses causing the pandemics of CMD and CBSD. The SSA-ECA genome assembled from Illumina short reads has a total size of 513.7 Mb and a scaffold N50 length of 497 kb, and contains 15,084 predicted protein-coding genes. Phylogenetic analysis suggests that SSA-ECA diverged from MEAM1 around 5.26 million years ago. A comprehensive genetic analysis of cassava-colonizing B. tabaci in Africa was also conducted, in which a total of 243 whitefly specimens were collected from 18 countries representing all major cassava-growing regions in the continent and genotyped using NextRAD sequencing. Population genomic analyses confirmed the existence of six major populations linked by gene flow and inferred the distribution patterns of these populations across the African continent. The genome of SSA-ECA and the genetic findings provide valuable resources and guidance to facilitate whitefly research and the development of strategies to control cassava viral diseases spread by whiteflies.</text><annotation id="21"><infon key="identifier">7038</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="14" offset="149"/><text>Bemisia tabaci</text></annotation><annotation id="22"><infon key="identifier">12081</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="5" offset="341"/><text>virus</text></annotation><annotation id="23"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="356"/><text>Cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="24"><infon key="identifier">7038</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="9" offset="375"/><text>B. tabaci</text></annotation><annotation id="25"><infon key="identifier">10239</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="395"/><text>viruses</text></annotation><annotation id="26"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="414"/><text>cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="27"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="447"/><text>cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="28"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="496"/><text>cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="29"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D014777</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="14" offset="543"/><text>viral diseases</text></annotation><annotation id="30"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="664"/><text>cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="31"><infon key="identifier">7038</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="9" offset="681"/><text>B. tabaci</text></annotation><annotation id="32"><infon key="identifier">10239</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="827"/><text>viruses</text></annotation><annotation id="33"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="1178"/><text>cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="34"><infon key="identifier">7038</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="9" offset="1197"/><text>B. tabaci</text></annotation><annotation id="35"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="1336"/><text>cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="36"><infon key="identifier">3983</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="1768"/><text>cassava</text></annotation><annotation id="37"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D014777</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="14" offset="1776"/><text>viral diseases</text></annotation></passage></document><document><id>31103803</id><passage><infon key="journal">J. Clin. Virol.; 2019 May 081 116 62-68. doi:10.1016/j.jcv.2019.05.003</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">Lobo SM, Watanabe ASA, Salomão MLM, Queiroz F, Gandolfi JV, de Oliveira NE, Covello LHS, Sacillotto GH, de Godoy LG, Simões ES, Frini ICM, Da Silva Teixeira RER, Furlan NP, Dutra KR, Nogueira ML, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>Excess mortality is associated with influenza A (H1N1) in patients with severe acute respiratory illness.</text><annotation id="2"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="8" offset="58"/><text>patients</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D012131</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="19" offset="85"/><text>respiratory illness</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>106</offset><text>BACKGROUND: Acute respiratory infections caused by viruses are among the leading causes of morbidity and mortality. The inflammatory response that follows viral infection is important for the control of virus proliferation. However, if overwhelming, may be associated with complicated outcomes. OBJECTIVES: We assessed the clinical characteristics of patients with severe acute respiratory illness (SARI) evolving to acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS) and the factors related to death. STUDY DESIGN: Prospective study in 273 adult patients with SARI performed in a university-affiliated 800-bed hospital serving an area of epidemiologic vigilance of 102 municipalities and more than 2 million inhabitants. Influenza A (H1N1) 2009 (A/H1N1), influenza A H3N2, and influenza B were tested in all patients by RT-PCR. RESULTS: The overall hospital mortality rate was 17.6%. A total of 30.4% of patients tested positive for influenza A/H1N1. Patients with SARI that evolved to ARDS took significantly longer to take the first dose of oseltamivir (6.0 vs 1.0 days, p=0.002). Patients with H1N1 positive tests had almost 3 times higher probability of death, despite having significantly less comorbidities (p=0.027). The influenza A/H1N1 pdm09 vaccine reduced the odds of death by 78%. Nonsurvivors had a more intense inflammatory response than did survivors at 48 h (C-reactive protein: 31.0 +- 17.5 vs. 14.6 +- 8.9 mg/dl, p=0.001) as well as a more positive fluid balance. CONCLUSIONS: Hospital mortality associated with influenza H1N1-associated SARI and ARDS continued to be high years after the 2009 pandemic in a population with low vaccine coverage. Antiviral treatment started more than two days after onset of symptoms was more frequently associated with ARDS and death and, having had vaccine against influenza A (H1N1) was a factor independently related to survival.</text><annotation id="23"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D012141</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="22" offset="124"/><text>respiratory infections</text></annotation><annotation id="24"><infon key="identifier">10239</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="157"/><text>viruses</text></annotation><annotation id="25"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D014777</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="15" offset="261"/><text>viral infection</text></annotation><annotation id="26"><infon key="identifier">12081</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="5" offset="309"/><text>virus</text></annotation><annotation id="27"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="8" offset="457"/><text>patients</text></annotation><annotation id="28"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D012131</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="19" offset="484"/><text>respiratory illness</text></annotation><annotation id="29"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D012128</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="29" offset="529"/><text>respiratory distress syndrome</text></annotation><annotation id="30"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003643</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="5" offset="593"/><text>death</text></annotation><annotation id="31"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="8" offset="645"/><text>patients</text></annotation><annotation id="32"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D006859</infon><infon key="type">Chemical</infon><location length="4" offset="866"/><text>H3N2</text></annotation><annotation id="33"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="8" offset="907"/><text>patients</text></annotation><annotation id="34"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="8" offset="1003"/><text>patients</text></annotation><annotation id="35"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="8" offset="1050"/><text>Patients</text></annotation><annotation id="36"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D053139</infon><infon key="type">Chemical</infon><location length="11" offset="1142"/><text>oseltamivir</text></annotation><annotation id="37"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="8" offset="1182"/><text>Patients</text></annotation><annotation id="38"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003643</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="5" offset="1257"/><text>death</text></annotation><annotation id="39"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003643</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="5" offset="1378"/><text>death</text></annotation><annotation id="40"><infon key="identifier">1401</infon><infon key="type">Gene</infon><infon key="NCBI Homologene">128039</infon><location length="18" offset="1474"/><text>C-reactive protein</text></annotation><annotation id="41"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003643</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="5" offset="1879"/><text>death</text></annotation></passage></document><document><id>31104021</id><passage><infon key="journal">J. Alzheimers Dis.; 2019 May 131 doi:10.3233/JAD-180958</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">McGurran H, Glenn JM, Madero EN, Bott NT, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>Prevention and Treatment of Alzheimer's Disease: Biological Mechanisms of Exercise.</text><annotation id="1"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="19" offset="28"/><text>Alzheimer's Disease</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>84</offset><text> Alzheimer's disease (AD) is the most common form of dementia. With an aging population and no disease modifying treatments available, AD is quickly becoming a global pandemic. A substantial body of research indicates that lifestyle behaviors contribute to the development of AD, and that it may be worthwhile to approach AD like other chronic diseases such as cardiovascular disease, in which prevention is paramount. Exercise is an important lifestyle behavior that may influence the course and pathology of AD, but the biological mechanisms underpinning these effects remain unclear. This review focuses on how exercise can modify four possible mechanisms which are involved with the pathology of AD: oxidative stress, inflammation, peripheral organ and metabolic health, and direct interaction with AD pathology. Exercise is just one of many lifestyle behaviors that may assist in preventing AD, but understanding the systemic and neurobiological mechanisms by which exercise affects AD could help guide the development of novel pharmaceutical agents and non-pharmacological personalized lifestyle interventions for at-risk populations.</text><annotation id="15"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="19" offset="85"/><text>Alzheimer's disease</text></annotation><annotation id="16"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="106"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="17"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D003704</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="8" offset="137"/><text>dementia</text></annotation><annotation id="18"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="219"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="19"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="360"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="20"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="406"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="21"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D002318</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="22" offset="445"/><text>cardiovascular disease</text></annotation><annotation id="22"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="594"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="23"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="784"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="24"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D007249</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="12" offset="806"/><text>inflammation</text></annotation><annotation id="25"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="887"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="26"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="980"/><text>AD</text></annotation><annotation id="27"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D000544</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="2" offset="1072"/><text>AD</text></annotation></passage></document><document><id>31104602</id><passage><infon key="journal">Philos. Trans. R. Soc. Lond., B, Biol. Sci.; 2019 Jul 081 37411776) 20180265. doi:10.1098/rstb.2018.0265</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">Kajero O, Del Rio Vilas V, Wood JLN, Lo Iacono G, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>New methodologies for the estimation of population vulnerability to diseases: a case study of Lassa fever and Ebola in Nigeria and Sierra Leone.</text><annotation id="1"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D007835</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="11" offset="94"/><text>Lassa fever</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>145</offset><text>Public health practitioners require measures to evaluate how vulnerable populations are to diseases, especially for zoonoses (i.e. diseases transmitted from animals to humans) given their pandemic potential. These measures would be valuable to support strategic and operational decision making and allocation of resources. Although vulnerability is well defined for natural hazards, for public health threats the concept remains undetermined. Here, we develop new methodologies to: (i) quantify the impact of zoonotic diseases and the capacity of countries to cope with these diseases, and (ii) combine these two measures (impact and capacity) into one overall vulnerability indicator. The adaptive capacity is calculated from estimations of disease mortality, although the method can be adapted for diseases with no or low mortality but high morbidity. As an example, we focused on the vulnerability of Nigeria and Sierra Leone to Lassa Fever and Ebola. We develop a simple analytical form that can be used to estimate vulnerability scores for different spatial units of interest, e.g. countries or regions. We show how some populations can be highly vulnerable despite low impact threats. We finally outline future research to more comprehensively inform vulnerability with the incorporation of relevant factors depicting local heterogeneities (e.g. bio-physical and socio-economic factors). This article is part of the theme issue 'Modelling infectious disease outbreaks in humans, animals and plants: epidemic forecasting and control'. This theme issue is linked with the earlier issue 'Modelling infectious disease outbreaks in humans, animals and plants: approaches and important themes'.</text><annotation id="9"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="6" offset="313"/><text>humans</text></annotation><annotation id="10"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D015047</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="17" offset="654"/><text>zoonotic diseases</text></annotation><annotation id="11"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D005334</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="5" offset="1083"/><text>Fever</text></annotation><annotation id="12"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D004195</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="28" offset="1580"/><text>Modelling infectious disease</text></annotation><annotation id="13"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="6" offset="1622"/><text>humans</text></annotation><annotation id="14"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D004195</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="28" offset="1736"/><text>Modelling infectious disease</text></annotation><annotation id="15"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="6" offset="1778"/><text>humans</text></annotation></passage></document><document><id>31105689</id><passage><infon key="journal">Front Immunol; 20191 10 756. doi:10.3389/fimmu.2019.00756</infon><infon key="year">2019</infon><infon key="article-id_pmc">PMC6499175</infon><infon key="type">title</infon><infon key="authors">Liu WC, Nachbagauer R, Stadlbauer D, Solórzano A, Berlanda-Scorza F, García-Sastre A, Palese P, Krammer F, Albrecht RA, </infon><offset>0</offset><text>Sequential Immunization With Live-Attenuated Chimeric Hemagglutinin-Based Vaccines Confers Heterosubtypic Immunity Against Influenza A Viruses in a Preclinical Ferret Model.</text><annotation id="2"><infon key="identifier">10239</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="135"/><text>Viruses</text></annotation><annotation id="3"><infon key="identifier">9669</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="6" offset="160"/><text>Ferret</text></annotation></passage><passage><infon key="type">abstract</infon><offset>174</offset><text>Due to continuous antigenic drift and occasional antigenic shift, influenza viruses escape from human adaptive immunity resulting in significant morbidity and mortality in humans. Therefore, to avoid the need for annual reformulation and readministration of seasonal influenza virus vaccines, we are developing a novel chimeric hemagglutinin (cHA)-based universal influenza virus vaccine, which is comprised of sequential immunization with antigens containing a conserved stalk domain derived from a circulating pandemic H1N1 strain in combination with "exotic" head domains. Here, we show that this prime-boost sequential immunization strategy redirects antibody responses toward the conserved stalk region. We compared the vaccine efficacy elicited by distinct vaccination approaches in the preclinical ferret model of influenza. All ferrets immunized with cHA-based vaccines developed stalk-specific and broadly cross-reactive antibody responses. Two consecutive vaccinations with live-attenuated influenza viruses (LAIV-LAIV) conferred superior protection against pH1N1 and H6N1 challenge infection. Sequential immunization with LAIV followed by inactivated influenza vaccine (LAIV-IIV regimen) also induced robust antibody responses. Importantly, the LAIV-LAIV immunization regimen also induced HA stalk-specific CD4+IFN-gamma+ and CD8+IFN-gamma+ effector T cell responses in peripheral blood that were recalled by pH1N1 viral challenge. The findings from this preclinical study suggest that an LAIV-LAIV vaccination regimen would be more efficient in providing broadly protective immunity against influenza virus infection as compared to other approaches tested here.</text><annotation id="12"><infon key="identifier">10239</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="250"/><text>viruses</text></annotation><annotation id="13"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="5" offset="270"/><text>human</text></annotation><annotation id="14"><infon key="identifier">9606</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="6" offset="346"/><text>humans</text></annotation><annotation id="15"><infon key="identifier">9669</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="6" offset="979"/><text>ferret</text></annotation><annotation id="16"><infon key="identifier">9669</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="1010"/><text>ferrets</text></annotation><annotation id="17"><infon key="identifier">10239</infon><infon key="type">Species</infon><location length="7" offset="1184"/><text>viruses</text></annotation><annotation id="18"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D007239</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="19" offset="1257"/><text>challenge infection</text></annotation><annotation id="19"><infon key="Identifier">MESH:D007251</infon><infon key="type">Disease</infon><location length="25" offset="1777"/><text>influenza virus infection</text></annotation></passage></document></collection>
